ALEXIS "Alex" FLORES ESCARCEGA

2510 Leon Street Austin, Texas 78705 (806) 319-3077

alex.floresescar@gmail.com

https://github.com/afloresescarcega

OBJECTIVE

To learn and apply as much knowledge from every subject into my field of profession by experience. To ultimately, advance into the technological field of Artificial Intelligence where it can be applied into everyday consumer goods and services.

COMPETENCIES

Git Arduino Python Programming
Self Motivated FPGA Design with VHDL Unix Shell Scripting
C Java Programming Fluent in Spanish

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas, May 2019.

Bachelor of ScienceMajor: **Computer Science**

Cumulative GPA: 3.7750

LANGUAGES

Spanish, first language English, fluent

EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Researcher at the University of Texas at Tyler Tyler, Texas, 2016-present.

- Self-study in the field of digital electronics design
- Investigating and learning the low-level interfaces between hardware and software
- Learning and using Hardware Description Languages to Synthesize Logic Circuits on FPGAs
- Conducting and analyzing tests using the C programming language on Unix operating systems

IEEE Robotics Teams at the University of Texas at Tyler Tyler, Texas, 2015-Present.

Team Member

- Built a set of robots from scrap and programmed with use of robust libraries
- Programmed Arduino microcontrollers in C
- Designed a non-hardcoded autonomous mode for navigation and object detection
- Often Referenced and changed the device libraries for robot
- Designed methods of digital communication between separate boards

LCHS Computer Science UIL Team Lubbock, Texas, 2013-2015.

Team Captain

- Taught and guided team members on computer programming techniques
- Practiced and refined Java programming practices
- Exercised problem solving strategies for hundreds of practice problems

Coronado High School Robotics, Lubbock, Texas, 2013-2014.

Team Member

- Programmed Micro-controllers in C
- Worked with the hardware team in implementing their visions

REFERENCES GIVEN UPON REQUEST